bharatwaves.co.in 2015-06-14

# Contribute

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. This policy applies to all information collected or submitted on the BharatWaves web site. 

Table Of Contents: 

  1. The Information We Collect 
  2. How We Use Information
  3. Cookies
  4. Log Files
  5. Links
  6. Recommend Us
  7. Our Commitment To Data Security 
  8. Business Transfers
  9. Our Commitment To Children's Privacy 
  10. How To Contact Us

* * *

**The Information We Collect:** (Top)

In order to make best use of this site you should register a user name with BharatWaves.com. The information you submit when registering in BharatWaves include following.

  * Real Name * 
  * User Name * 
  * Password * 
  * Email Address * 
  * Personal Avatar (a picture that represents you) 
  * Personal Website 
  * Instant Messenger Information (ICQ, AIM, YIM, MSNM) 
  * Geographic Location 
  * Occupation 
  * Interests 
  * Additional Information 

The types above marked with an asterisk (*) indicates required fields. The other fields are optional and are provided only to facilitate your communication with others.  Your email address is visible to users only if you check "Allow other users to view my email address " while regiserting in BharatWaves.   

On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you would like to let someone know about this website via our "Recommend Us " instant e-mail service, you will need to submit the recipient's e-mail address.   

**How We Use Information:** (Top)

We never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. 

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals. 

Other than your user name and personal avatar, you may choose which pieces of information are viewable to others when registering. You can modify this at any time using the "Edit Profile" option. Other users will be able to see your current user name, your current personal avatar, as well as the posts, articles, and comments you have submitted. 

We reserve the right to transfer your information to a third party for the purposes of managing normal aspects of our business.  For instance, we may contract with an e-mail newsletter service or an accounting/bookkeeping service. 

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

**Cookies** : (Top)

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. Some of our business partners may elect to use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. 

**Log Files:** (Top) ****

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.   

**Links:** (Top)

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we BharatWaves.com are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.   

**Recommed Us:** (Top) ****

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. BharatWaves.com will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. BharatWaves.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. The friend may contact BharatWaves.com at info@bharatwaves.com to request the removal of this information from database. 

**Our Commitment To Data Security:** (Top)

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. However, you should be aware that this system may never be completely secure. This site is virtually hosted and uses the XOOPS and PHP based content management systems.  Both use a MYSQL database backend and various third party modules. Our system is subject to any security vulnerabilities attributable to these software and systems. Although it is an unlikely event, it is possible that your data could be purposefully accessed through these vulnerabilities. 

We may choose to release account and other personal information when appropriate in order to comply with the law or to enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements.  It may also be necessary to release information for the purpose of protecting the rights, property, or safety of BharatWaves, our users, or others. This would include the exchange of information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

**Business Transfers:** (Top)

As we continue to develop our business, we might choose to sell or buy portions of our business.  You should know that in these transactions, customer information are typically one of the business assets transferred but will remain subject to promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Notice. Also, in the event that all or a portion of BharatWaves is acquired, customer information will likely be one of the transferred assets. 

**Our Commitment To Children's Privacy:** (Top)

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important to us. 

Unfortunately, we cannot determine whether or not a subscriber to our site is under the age of 13.  As a parent you should be aware of what site's your child visits.  Our assurance to you is that we will attempt to make this site family friendly.  However, we cannot always control the language used by our other members.

If you find something offensive on our site and we will review the issue immediately.  If feel your child is being harassed or endangered by anyone participating on this site, let us know immediately so that we can deal with the situation.

If you would not like your child's information stored on our database, please let us know and we will either establish an alias so that they can still enjoy the site to it's fullest degree, or we will delete the record entirely. 

If you are under the age of 18 you should involve your parent or guardian before engaging in any financial transactions with BharatWaves.com

**How To Contact Us:** (Top)

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please use contact us form to communicate with us.
